Julien COLOMB, PhD

Schillerpromenade 4 12049 Berlin julien.colomb@fu-berlin.de

Birth: 9 April 1979 in Sion (CH) Single, one child

Swiss



Personal statement

I am a professional neuro-geneticist, and used the fruit fly, *Drososphila melanogaster*, as a model organism for more than ten years. During that time, I grew a tight social network with other "drosophilists", and could experienced the daily activities in the lab and the shortcomings in lab management and scientific communication in different labs in Europe (Switzerland, France and Germany).

Experience

 $10~{\rm Years'}$ experience in Scientific activities, including team management, student supervision, teaching and grant writing.

A bit about me.

I am a father of one child. At 36 I am choosing to put my scientific career on the side, in order to stay in Berlin and focus on the development of digital tools for scientists and embrace the open science movement.

Research activities

2014	Postdoctoral fellow	HU & C	harite (Berlin,	Germany),	by Prof.	Y.
------	---------------------	--------	-----------------	-----------	----------	----

Winter

The handbook for behavioural diagnostic in rodents.

2009-2013 **Postdoctoral fellow**, FU (**Berlin**, Germany), by Prof. B. Brembs

the what and where of operant learning in *Drosophila*.

2007-2008 Postdoctoral fellow, ESPCI (Paris, France), by Dr. T. Preat

appetitive learning in *Drosophila*.

Education

2013 Moderation & management (Continuing Education), FU Berlin/Artop. PhD in Biology, University of Fribourg (Fribourg, Switzerland). 2006 PhD dissertation: "The chemosensory system of Drosophila larvae: neuroanatomy and behaviour" Thesis director: Prof. R.F Stocker Diploma in Biology, University of Fribourg (Fribourg, Switzerland) 2002 "Maturité fédérale type C" (scientific subsection), in the "Collège de la 1998 royale Abbaye de St. Maurice"

References (available on request)

Prof. Y. Winter, HU Berlin Prof. B. Brembs, Uni Regensburg Prof. T. Preat, ESPCI, Paris

Approved grants

DFG Forschungsgruppe "biogenic amines in insects", cowritten with Dr. 2010 Brembs. SNF for a vanced researchers: PA00P3-124141 - "The what and where 2009 of operant learning in *Drosophila*" $\overline{\rm SNF}$ for prospective researchers: PBFR33-116951 - "Memory phases of 2007

reward learning in Drosophila melanogaster"

Languages

French (mother tongue), English (fluent), German (fluent), Spanish (basics).

Research output metrics

h-index =6,

Open source software: 2 (1 first author), Research papers: 10 (6 first author), Meeting Presentations = 25

Supervision of student

2010-2015 Co-supervisor of the PhD student Christine Damrau Co-supervisor of the PhD student Séverine Trannoy 2008 Co-supervisor of the diploma work of Claire Huguenin 2005

Computer skills

Publishing: LaTeX, Office; html; Image processing: Photoshop, Illustrator, Image J; Programming: Labview, R (freeware for statistics), Git

Other tasks

Creation of the T. Preat's and R.F. Stocker's lab website. Co-director in the theater group "les apostrophes" in 2006 Cashier of and actor in the theater group "les apostrophes" in 2002-2005.